<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Speakers on</title><link>/speakers/</link><description>Recent content in Speakers on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="/speakers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Iain Matthews</title><link>/speakers/iain-matthews-iain-matthews/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/speakers/iain-matthews-iain-matthews/</guid><description>&lt;p>Iain Matthews is an experienced research director with respected contributions in both industry and academia. Iain received a BEng degree in electronic engineering and a PhD in computer science from the University of East Anglia in the UK. He moved to the USA to join the Robotics Institute at Carnegie Mellon University. In 2006 he spent two years in New Zealand at the visual effects company Weta Digital contributing to the FACETS facial motion capture system while working on the movies Avatar and Tintin, and was awarded a Scientific and Engineering Award (a technical Oscar) for this work in 2017. He joined the newly formed Disney Research in Pittsburgh in 2008 to build the computer vision group and in 2013 was promoted to Associate Director of the Pittsburgh lab. Prior to joining Epic Games he spent a couple of years at Oculus Research / Facebook Reality Labs working on social VR/AR.
Iain also holds a courtesy faculty appointment at the Robotics Institute at Carnegie Mellon University and an Honorary Professor position at the University of East Anglia. He has published over 140 academic papers and been issued more than 25 US patents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yukie Nagai</title><link>/speakers/yukie-nagai-yukie-nagai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/speakers/yukie-nagai-yukie-nagai/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yukie Nagai is a Project Professor at the International Research Center for Neurointelligence at the University of Tokyo. She earned her Ph.D. in Engineering from Osaka University in 2004, after which she worked at the National Institute of Information and Communications Technology, Bielefeld University, and then Osaka University. Since 2019, she has been leading the Cognitive Developmental Robotics Lab at the University of Tokyo. Her research encompasses cognitive developmental robotics, computational neuroscience, and assistive technologies for developmental disorders. Dr. Nagai employs computational methods to investigate the underlying neural mechanisms involved in social cognitive development. In acknowledgment of her work, she was elected to &amp;lsquo;World&amp;rsquo;s 50 Most Renowned Women in Robotics&amp;rsquo; in 2020, &amp;lsquo;35 Women in Robotics Engineering and Science&amp;rsquo; in 2022, and &amp;lsquo;Forbes JAPAN Women In Tech 30&amp;rsquo; in 2024, among other recognitions.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>